no beginning... no end... no speed limit...
Two-Lane Blacktop is a drama film directed by Monte Hellman.
A driver and mechanic drag racing for money cross paths with a female
hitchhiker and a drifter who challenges them to a cross-country race.
The Driver, played by James Taylor.
G.T.O., played by Warren Oates.
The Mechanic, played by Dennis Wilson.
The Girl, played by Laurie Bird.
Hot Rod Driver, played by Rudy Wurlitzer.
Oklahoma Hitchhiker, played by Harry Dean Stanton.
Two-Lane Blacktop is a 1971 American road film directed and edited by Monte
Hellman, from a screenplay by Rudy Wurlitzer and Will Corry.
It stars musicians James Taylor and Dennis Wilson, Warren
Oates, and Laurie Bird in the leading roles.
The sparse, existentialist plot follows a group of street racers during
a cross-country race through the American Southwest.
Universal Pictures commissioned the film in the wake
of Easy Rider's monumental success.
Hellman, who had previously worked in low-budget and independent films, developed the screenplay with
Wurlitzer, then-known mainly as an underground writer, during an actual cross-country road trip.
Filming took place in locations around the
Southwest between August and October 1970.
On initial release, the film received generally positive
reviews, but was not a commercial success.
Over the years, it developed the reputation of a sleeper hit and a cult classic, and
has been reevaluated as a major work of the New Hollywood movement.
In 2012, the US Library of Congress selected the film for preservation in the United States
National Film Registry as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant."
The film explores themes of car race, car mechanic,
chevrolet, road movie, drag race.
The tone is emotional.